Finding aid for the Machado and Silvetti Getty Villa renovation design records, 1994-2004 IA10019
Institutional Records and Archives
- Project planning and administration, 1993-2001; Series III.; 45.2 Linear Feet (27 boxes, 6 flat files)
  - Peter Lofgren files, 1993-1998; Series III.A.; 41.1 Linear Feet (24 boxes, 6 flat files)
    - Drawings, 1994-2000
      - Bid sets, comments and corrections, 1998-2000
        - Museum door detail mark-ups, June 30, 1999; (set of black-and-white prints, 15 x 21 inches) (Box 2004.IA.06-131)
        - Ranch House bid set, architecture only, June 30, 1999; (set of blueline prints, 15 x 21 inches) (Box 2004.IA.06-131)
        - Museum bid set, June 30, 1999; (set of blueline prints, 15 x 21 inches) (Box 2004.IA.06-131)
        - Museum bid set with museum coordination comments, January 11, 2000; (set of black-and-white prints, 15 x 21 inches) (Box 2004.IA.06-131)
      - Blueprint, blueline and black-and-white plans, 1994-1998
        - Site plan, November 30, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-114)
        - Project schedule visual representation, 1994-1995 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-132)
        - Blueprint and blueline civil and geo-technical survey plans and comments, 1994-1995 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-134)
        - Blueprint and blueline civil survey plans and related paperwork, 1994-1995 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-133)
        - Blueprint and blueline drawings, plans and elevations, 1994-1996 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-132)
        - Loose materials: structural wall layout, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-116)
          [Structural wall layout for parking, basement, first floor, second floor, first floor (Ranch House), and second floor (Ranch House).]
        - Entitlements: blueprint and blueline Phase II site plan and front elevation, 1995 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-139)
        - Scope modifications: blueline and black-and-white site plans and mock-ups, 1995-1996 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-137)
        - Loose materials: drawings, sketches, notes, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-116)
        - Loose materials: basement, ground and second level plans, January 1996; undated (Box 2004.IA.06-116)
        - Reference log: blueprint, blueline and black-and-white casework elevation drawings, schematic designs and design development sets, 1996-1997 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-136)
        - Reference log: blueprint, blueline and black-and-white drawings, design development sets, site plans, and elevations, 1996-1998 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-135)
        - Reference log: blueprint, blueline and black-and-white ranch house lighting layouts and reflected ceiling plans, 1997-1998 (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-138)
        - Blueprint, blueline and black-and-white plans, undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-139)
  - Tim Love files, 1993-2001; Series III.B.; 4.1 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
    These records comprise Machado and Silvetti associate Tim Love's (Associate in charge of the Masterplan Team, 1993-1996, Project Manager and Senior Designer, 1996-2002) files relating to the renovation of the Getty Villa dating from 1993-2001. They consist of administrative files, blueline prints, blueprints, black-and-white prints, and drawings.
    This material serves as an overview and summary of the project stages and includes materials relating to budget, scheduling, contracts, and work with consultants including landscape and lighting design. Extensive meeting minutes and notes are also included.
    - Meeting minutes and materials, 1994-2001
      Contains Tim Love's meeting materials, minutes, agendas and notes.
      - Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Meeting minutes: Langdon and Wilson, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Meeting agendas, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Machado and Silvetti meeting minutes and notes, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty generated meeting minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty trustees meeting prep, 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - Getty trustees meeting material, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty generated meeting minutes, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Meeting minutes, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty meetings, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty meetings, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Agendas, schedules, February 20, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - General meeting minutes, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - General meeting minutes, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - Agendas, meeting planning, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty meetings, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - General meeting minutes, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty estimates and meeting materials, 1999-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty estimates and meeting materials, 2000-2001 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
    - Project files, 1993-2000
      Contains Tim Love's project files from the Getty Villa renovation. The files cover specific issues addressed over the course of his involvement with the project.
      The material is arranged in rough chronological order.
      - Getty "mission statement," institutional descriptions, 1993-1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Design notes from Getty visits and presentation materials, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Previous studies, expansion feasibility report, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Vendors, consultant solicitation, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Consultant correspondence, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Fire, emergency access, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Traffic, parking, parking garage, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Transmittals, 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - ADA: building code reviews, E.I.R., 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Contract / fee issues, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Project schedules, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - Structural, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - Landscape, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Cost estimation, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Directories, long range schedules, 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - "Cost estimation: schematic design, including January 1996 estimate,", 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty analysis, circa 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Fee discussions, general project management, 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-140)
      - Getty, clippings (general), 1995-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Design development: design sketches, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty: entitlements process, 1995-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Dinwiddie September budget, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty contract, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Machado & Silvetti exhibitions / publications / public lectures, 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Millwork / furniture, 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Schematic design: design issues and presentation outlines, circa 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Contract, 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - "DD slope 'creep' issues,", 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Contractor selection, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Post-DD schedules, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - "Post DD materials (specification),", 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Post design development, cost estimation, project budget, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Millwork package, storage package, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-122)
      - Architecture magazine submission, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - LAM Partners, lighting, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Landscape, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - "Getty current," general contractor contracts, display case cost comparison, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Fee and contract issues, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty opening exhibition at Brentwood, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Design development: cost estimates, schedules, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - "Pedestal meeting, museum design issues,", 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Morley construction pricing / value engineering, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Contract, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - "E.I.R. Getty,", 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Value engineering / cost savings ideas, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Budgets, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Signage, furniture, lighting, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Phase I additional services schedule extension, 1997-1999 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Design mock-up, sample issues, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - "Important memos (Rountree, project policy, etc),", 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty construction administration, fee schedule, staffing, 1998-1999 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Phase II scope of work, fees, contract, 1998-1999 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Phase II fee analysis, 1999 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty trip, April 2000 (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
      - Getty xeroxed readings, undated (Box 2004.IA.06-141)
  - Planning photographs, undated; Series III.C.; 0.75 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
    Series III.C. consists of undated albums of photographs from research and planning trips related to the design of the Getty Villa, including a trip to France.
    Materials have been maintained in original order.
    - Villa European trip, undated (Box 2004.IA.06-143)
    - Photographs (binder 1/2), undated (Box 2004.IA.06-144)
    - Photographs (binder 2/2), undated (Box 2004.IA.06-145)